Peter Ciardullo

Italo-Brazilian based in Dublin/Ireland

Dublin, County Dublin D01HH56 peter.ciardullo@gmail.com +353 83 447 7683

I am a 37 years old professional very passionate to exceed the expectation, challenge lover and always open to communication and learn new ways to develop results.

I am always looking to not just hit the target, but also to over that target and recommend a better solution for the known process.

Responsible for share all the information that help other on my team to have a better solution for each jobseeker.

Personal Details

Highest Level of Education: Bachelor's

Industry: Legal

Work Experience

Customer Care Advisor

Allianz - Dublin, County Dublin January 2023 to Present

- Responsible for manage customers queries about the Table of Benefits, Coverages, Premium, and all documents for insurance group or private;
- Analysis and verification about coverage, pre approval, and all information about insurance routine;
- Follow the guidelines, in order to hit the targets, metrics (quality evaluations).

Hospitality Host on board - Enterprise train

Corporate Catering Services - Dublin, County Dublin August 2022 to Present

- Help and serve passengers on first class for the trains to Belfast, both ways.
- Service on board preparing orders, serving teas, coffees, minerals, sandwiches, snacks and beverages.
- Customer Service in the kitchen/bar with full Irish breakfast or meal.
- Serving customers to support a good and comfortable journey.

Job Seeker Success Advisor (Content Moderator) - English/Portuguese

Concentrix, Swords - Dublin, County Dublin May 2021 to Present

• Responsible for driving the queries of the Job Seekers to the correct answer following guidelines, quality evaluations and criteria.

- Reply emails in Portuguese and English language addressing the solution for the issue and starting investigation when there is suspicion of fraud/scam.
- Follow up these investigations with the Job Seekers, asking for extra material or information, also supporting the Trust & Safety team.
- Analyses and identification of fraud when a jobseeker contacts us, flagging to the client for additional investigation and also advising the jobseekers on how to proceed, guiding via articles, and the regular procedure.
- Flagging to the client the trends in the queue providing examples, and evidence to support the indication of fraud/scam monitoring ongoing fraud and scam trends in different markets (US, IE, UK, CA, BR, PT, ND, IN, etc).
- Perfect understanding and knowledge about GDPR and CCPA in the EMEA and AMER regions.
- Supporting the Quality team indicating the inaccurate information or incorrect place advertised on the client site, to be corrected.
- Providing feedback for the other agents with Feedback sessions, demonstrating the correct workflow, issue resolution, and all the information provided by the client and followed by the agents.
- Quality Assurance Evaluations on week basis driven other Agents to hit the targets and metrics, sharing articles, guidelines in a well structured email after a Zoom feedback session.
- Working on chat support to give to the candidates the correct solution in real time and a few minutes, to improve the CSAT and quantities of solved tickets.
- Support in real time via Chat, helping employers and job seekers, troubleshooting, change dispositions remotely, making changes and helping in every step during interview sessions.
- Able to suggest new tools and upgrades to increase efficiency and productivity to the team.
- Very familiarized with Zendesk software, Waldo, SQL, Django, ACME, BOSS, Mechabugs, Jira and the basic softwares files like Word, Acrobat (PDF), Excel, Access, etc.
- Employer of the quarter for the client after research and producing a presentation on how to improve the Customer Satisfaction Rate (CSTA) in the Surveys from the jobseekers.
- Working on moderations of tickets from other agents, in order to create the best experience for job seekers, answering their questions and solving the issue at the first reply.
- Treinament for the new tools provided by the cliente, and fast learning on how to use and increase the accuracy on every reply, reproducing successful situations to the rest of the team in order to help others.
- Recognized as exceeding expectations for 2022 receiving an increase on the wages and always entitled to receive the quarter bonus since not just hitting the targets, but exceeding them.
- Working as a team worker supporting the new hires and replying question using the proper channel.
- Shadowing sessions to explain procedures, tips, and pass ahead all knowledge for the new hires.
- Updating presentation with best practices in a day-by-day basis in order to help the team to work efficiently and smoothly.

Senior On-Board Steward at Irish Rail

Rail Gourmet - Dublin, County Dublin October 2019 to May 2021

I was responsible for:

- Passengers on first class for the trains to Cork, both ways.
- Service on board on the trains to Galway, Limerick, Cork, Westport, Waterford, Tralee.
- Senior Service on board for passengers in first class to Cork.
- Customer Service with trolley on board, or in the kitchen/bar with full Irish breakfast or meal.
- Serving customers with snacks, minerals, drinks, sandwiches, crisps, tea, coffee, and everything to support a good and comfortable journey.

Waiter/Camarieri

Alexander Bar and Restaurant - Piverone, IT July 2019 to October 2019

Italy

- Responsible for meeting and greeting customers,
- Responsible for taking orders from customers,
- Responsible for cleaning the tables, taking orders to pizzeria or kitchen,
- Delivering drinks and answering every question for customers in general.

Consumer vs Social Media Freelancer

Self employed worked for my self August 2018 to February 2019

A case between my client and a Social Media company who was contracted to keep professional details and all information in a cloud base data where could be shared just between companies (looking for a position in these companies) after a previous agreement.

• After my client cancelled the contract (because she started in a new job), the company continued with her

details and worst sharing her personal information to other companies but not to offer a position to my client, it was to offer services, products, and all kinds of spam advertisement.

• After a few meetings, there was no deal with social media representatives (who defended not shared information but shared their database in total), so I elaborated a procedure in a Civil Special Court (JEC) place for

small cases because it is faster than a Civil Court (depends on the theme and amount involved).

• In our first conciliation hearing, we made a deal, given that the offer from the Social Media company was accepted for my client to end up the procedure (judicial deal).

On-Board Steward

Rail Gourmet - Dublin, County Dublin May 2018 to February 2019

- Dublin.
- Boarding on the trains to Galway, Limerick, Cork, Westport, Waterford,

Tralee.

- Senior Service on board for passengers in first class to Cork.
- Customer Service with trolley on board, or in the kitchen/bar with full Irish breakfast or meal.
- Serving customers with snacks, minerals, drinks, sandwiches, crisps, tea, coffee, and everything to support a good and comfortable journey.

Freelancer (Remote-Brazil)

Bank Institution

March 2018 to May 2018

Consumer vs Bank Institution

- Responsible for elaborating a letter informing that the consumer rights were not being respected because my client was improperly charged many times. I demonstrated there was a mistake in a system bank validation code (by the application that time token).
- To sum up a made deal (extrajudicial deal) between my client and the bank, in a confidential amount plus a compromise to turn the application better to not cause another incident (or the bank would be fined).

Regulatory Analyst II

Nextel Telecomunicações Ltda April 2015 to September 2016

Brazil

- Implement and follower of Customers Counsel reunions (Resolution nº 623/2013) around four regions in Brazil (different states);
- Making improvement plans, checking spreadsheets and tables of Due Diligence processes in the company.
- I was responsible for calculating and evaluate the amount possible fine in each procedure, each procedure was classified as remote, possible or probable (chances to win), and to send this information to finance area to separate the amount in your provision table, in case of losing any appeal or reconsideration we were able to pay the fine, and procedure to pay

and transfer the amount to Anatel was my duty;

- Follow procedures in Anatel (Telecommunications Regulatory Agency in Brazil), doing administrative defence and/or appeal in PADOs (Obligations non-compliance procedure),
- PAVDs (Report Investigation Procedure), Administrative Complaint, Reports from another providers/ players, documents responses, as spreadsheets, tables, control reports, thesis, search, and everything about Telecommunications Law, specifically in providers relationships, analyse and making contracts between providers to share infrastructure and to sell dedicated products to players.
- Regulatory risk analysis in contracts, negotiations, payments and direct reports. I have travelled to Brasilia (Brazil capital) as a legal representative in forums, congress and audience in Anatel.

Regulatory Analyst I (Junior)

Telefônica Brasil S.A October 2012 to April 2015

Follow inspections around Brazil with support to shops, inspectors and auditors from Anatel, elaborations of improvement plans, verifications of spreadsheets, tables about customers refunds, interruptions of the service and actions plans.

- I was responsible to follow every procedure in Anatel, updates, changes, everything, and elaboration of administrative defence and/or appeal in PADOs (Obligations non-compliance procedure), PAVDs (Report Investigation Procedure), Administrative Complaint, Reports from another providers/players, documents responses or reconsiderations;
- I was responsible to amount possible fine in each procedure, each procedure was classified as remote, possible or probable (chances to win), and to send this information to finance area to separate the amount in your provision table;
- Follow procedures in Anatel (Telecommunications Agency in Brazil), like spreadsheets, tables, control reports, thesis, search, and everything about Telecommunications Law, tables controls and answering external auditors companies (Ernest & Young, PriceWaterhouse, KPMG);
- I was responsible to follow all administrative procedures about Anatel, elaboration of some administrative appeals in PADOs, PAVDs, answer documents, as a support every lawyer in our team (around ten lawyers). Elaboration of tables and spreadsheets, controls, exhibition in PowerPoint of critical points, researches and materials to support our team to build a good defences theses about Telecommunications Law;
- I have diligently spent some time at Anatel office in Sao Paulo/SP to do document protocols and to participate in meetings and discussions about improvement plans.

Education

Junior Certificate in Return to work

Irish Times Training - Dublin March 2021 to June 2021

Advanced/Higher Certificate in Digital Law

Presbyterian University Mackenzie - São Paulo, SP January 2012 to December 2012

Bachelor's in Law

Presbyterian University Mackenzie - São Paulo, SP January 2007 to June 2011

Skills

- Customer service
- Time management
- Restaurant experience
- Serving
- Bartending
- · Barista experience
- Restaurant management
- Cash handling
- Legal Research (5 years)
- Moderation (2 years)
- Agile
- Zendesk
- Django
- Jira
- · Organisational skills
- Sparkspot (Less than 1 year)
- Lookup tool (Less than 1 year)
- Side conversations (Less than 1 year)
- SQL (Less than 1 year)
- Hospitality
- Microsoft Word
- Typing
- Microsoft Outlook
- Microsoft Word
- Microsoft Powerpoint
- · Communication skills

- Budgeting
- Microsoft Powerpoint
- Telecommunication
- Negotiation
- Administrative experience

Languages

- Portuguese Expert
- Italian Intermediate
- English Expert
- Spanish Beginner

Links

https://www.linkedin.com/in/peterciardullo/

Assessments

Health & safety — Proficient

January 2021

Using safe practices at work

Full results: Proficient

Attention to detail — Expert

December 2021

Identifying differences in materials, following instructions and detecting details from among distracting

information

Full results: Expert

Customer focus & orientation — Proficient

December 2021

Responding to customer situations with sensitivity

Full results: Proficient

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.